Rhodri Smith

Fishguard, Pembrokeshire SA65 9DB, rhodrigsmith@gmail.com, 07500 362730

GitHub Repositories: https://github.com/Rhod4?tab=repositories

I am a software developer with over 2 years of experience, currently working at Writemedia. Within this role, I work on front-end, backend and mobile development. Front-end websites are my main skill set. My aim is always to create high-quality user experience, while always keeping a modern UI approach.

Professional Experience

Writemedia:

Full Stack Web and Flutter Developer

Pembroke Dock - January 2022 to June 2024

Writemedia is an agency software development company, meaning that I worked on many different projects for a number of different companies, including the WRU, Create Development and Agrify. Wales. The projects for these companies required me to work on very old technologies, to most recent ones.

• Front-end development:

Creating front end projects using HTML, JavaScript and CSS. Within these I also used frameworks to help with the development of projects, such as Typescript, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Vue, Axios, PrimeVue and JQuery. Most of my experience is with NuxtJs/Vue and Typescript

ASP.NET MVC and Minimal API to build web APIs:

Using C# to create backend projects. These being ASP.NET MVC, Minimal Api, and API projects using the MVC framework but not the view pages.

• Database manipulation with EF Core and SQL gueries:

I have used EF Core and Dapper to manipulate databases; Dapper allows the use of stored procedure and SQL queries within C#, while EF Core allowed me to use built-in methods. I was required to work on the live databases as well.

Mobile development with Flutter:

I have used Flutter for creating mobile applications; allowing me to simultaneously create IOS and Android applications using the same code base. I was also tasked with publishing both the applications to their associated store.

• Team Working:

In Writemedia, we followed a scrum-based approach to working and required code to be reviewed, before being pushed to our main or staging git branches.

UI and UX Design:

I used Figma to create high and low-fidelity front end wireframes, as well as user flow diagrams

• Knowledge and experience of using TTD:

With the newer projects within the business, we had used TTD with fluent validation, this being run locally and on our repository's pull requests.

Notable Projects:

- Implemented i18n into one of the APIs to support both Welsh and English languages.
- Refactored a significant MVC SaaS application to meet WCAG 2.0 AA accessibility standards.
- I created a front-end web application for mobile devices, which was later needed to be directly replicated in flutter, reusing the same API endpoints
- I have also been part of creating a sales platform for a greenfield SaaS app that provides sports

education for primary school children through an app. Umbraco was integrated into this site to allow the user to have a CMS.

• In one of my personal projects, I used ASP.NET Core Minimal API as my API framework, and then NuxtJs with DaisyUi to create the front end.

BCC IT

Service Desk Technician

Newcastle Emlyn - October 2021 to December 2021

BCC IT is an IT support business for businesses

While working at BCC IT I was on the service desk, this meant that it was my responsibility to create, update and complete any ticket assigned to me. My role was to resolve any IT issues a user had, which could range from password resets, to trying to investigate more complex issues, an example of this would be a trackpad not working.

Summer Jobs

CSE - Fishguard - June 2018 to September 2019

Summer job, over two Summers working at a company called CSE. I also spent a Summer prior to working with CSE working in The Royal Oak Fishguard.

Work Experience -

Solva Primary School - Solva 2016 to 2016

For my Welsh Bacc work experience I supported in Solva Primary School for a week.

Interests

I have spent 15 years as part of Sea Cadets, 8 as a cadet, and 7 years as a voluntary staff member and I am still actively involved with the organization. During my time in Sea Cadets, I have gained a vast amount of different skills and knowledge, including leading, teaching and being an effective team member. Through Sea Cadets, I have recently obtained my RYA PBI, which allows me to teach powerboating with and outside of cadets.

I am a Welsh speaker who takes great pride in my work, and I am passionate to further my experience and skills in my role of a software developer

Education

Bachelor's in Computer Science, G400 -Aberystwyth University - Aberystwyth September 2017 to June 2020 Diploma of Higher Education in Level 3 Extended DIP in IT

Pembrokeshire College – Haverfordwest September 2015 to June 2017 GCSE or equivalent in ICT, Welsh, English, Sciences, Maths, D&T Ysgol Bro Gwaun - Pembrokeshire September 2009 to August 2015